Guide to the John Howard Griffin Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
- Series III: Shorter Writings 1950s
  - Griffin, John Howard "Nuestra Senora de la Resurreccion", Mansfield, Texas, [n.d.], (9 page t.ms. (carbon) (Box 3, Folder 104)
    [This is a piece written about the Benedictine monastery located between Mexico City and Cuernavaca. One of Griffin's abiding passions was the study of the monastic life. In the case of this piece, he did hope to publish it but was not successful. Nonetheless, in writing it, he was consistent in his ongoing interest in monasticism. Several of his short stories of this period are about characters in monasteries--both serious, like "Metamorphosis" and comic, like the Friar Clud stories. His first novel, The Devil Rides Outside, takes place in part in a monastery. Relating in general to this passion for the monastic life are his lectures on Gregorian Chant, combining the roots of monasticism with the flower of medieval music.
  - Griffin, John Howard "Preface" to the Dallas lectures on Gregorian Chant, [n.p.], [n.d.], (7 page t.ms.) (Box 3, Folder 105)
  - Griffin, John Howard Notes on music used in lecture, [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 page t.ms.) (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - Griffin, John Howard Notes on Music Article, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 page t.ms.) (Box 13, Folder 451)
  - Griffin, John Howard Dallas lecture number one: "Preliminary study of Modality", [n.p.], [n.d.], (25 page t.ms.) (Box 3, Folder 107)
  - Griffin, John Howard Dallas lecture number two: "Neum notation and Modality", [n.p.], 23 Feb. [n.y.], (10 page t.ms.) (Box 3, Folder 108)
  - Griffin, John Howard Dallas lecture number three: "Rhythm", [n.p.], [n.d.], (8 page t.ms.) (Box 3, Folder 109)
  - Griffin, John Howard 18 Lectures on the History of Music. Introduction and recordings list, Forth Worth, Texas, [n.d.], (9 page t.ms.) (Box 3, Folder 110)
  - Griffin, John Howard 18 lectures on the history of music: lecture one, Forth Worth, Texas, [n.d.], (24 page t.ms. (with ms. corrections) (Box 3, Folder 111)
  - Griffin, John Howard 18 lectures on the history of music: lecture two, Forth Worth, Texas, [n.d.], (7 page t.ms.) (Box 3, Folder 112)
  - Griffin, John Howard 18 lectures on the history of music: lecture three, Forth Worth, Texas, [n.d.], (10 page t.ms.) (Box 3, Folder 113)
  - Griffin, John Howard 18 lectures on music: lecture seven, Fort Worth, Texas, [n.d.], (7 page t.ms.) (Box 3, Folder 114)
  - Griffin, John Howard 18 lectures on music: lecture for Feb. 2nd, Fort Worth, Texas, [n.d.], (3 page t.ms.) (Box 3, Folder 115)
  - Griffin, John Howard 18 lectures on music: lecture for Feb. 19th, Fort Worth, Texas, [n.d.], (3 page t.ms.) (Box 3, Folder 116)
  - Griffin, John Howard 18 lectures on music: lecture on Mozart, Fort Worth, Texas, [n.d.], (4 page t.ms.) (Box 3, Folder 117)
  - Griffin, John Howard 18 lectures on music: lecture 15, Fort Worth, Texas, [n.d.], (14 page t.ms.) (Box 3, Folder 118)
  - Griffin, John Howard 18 lecture on music: modern music, Fort Worth, Texas, [n.d.], (5 page t.ms.) (Box 3, Folder 119)
  - Griffin, John Howard Detroit Lecture on Gregorian Chant, [Detroit], 28 Feb. 1954, (10 page t.ms.) (Box 3, Folder 120)
- Series IV: Nuni, Street of the Seven Angels, Passacaglia
  These are the three novels drafted by Griffin during the 1950s while he was still sightless. Only Nuni was published, in 1956. One chapter from Street was published as a short story in 1957.
  - Subseries IV.1: Nuni
    - Griffin, John Howard Nuni, Texas, 14 December 1955, (243 page t.ms. (carbon) in, 1 volume) (Box 3, Folder 121)
      [The final draft of the novel, complete with the author's changes and comments in longhand.. The original manuscript, as well as the manuscripts for The Devil Rides Outside and Land of the High Sky (all published between 1952 and 1959) have not survived. The publishers have indicated that the original manuscripts were returned to Griffin. Yet it is the carbons he kept in his archives which reveal his working process.. The carbons reveal all of his changes. Either he used these carbons for his own purposes, to catalog the changes made on the originals or even on the galleys (for no galleys survive either), or the typesetting of the galleys was made directly from these carbons
    - Mosely, Hardwick To Clyde P. Holland [Griffin's business manager], Houghton Mifflin Co., Boston, 3 January 1956, (1 t.l.s.) (Box 3, Folder 123)
    - Hawkes, Wendy To Elizabeth Griffin-Bonazzi, Houghton Mifflin Co., Boston, 7 December 1984 (Box 3, Folder 124)
      [ With photocopy of renewal document from Houghton Mifflin.
    - News stories and book reviews of Nuni, (4 pages photocopy) (Box 3, Folder 125)
    - Eugene McNamara Offprints of articles about Nuni and Devil (Box 3, Folder 126)
      [Canadian critic
    - Griffin, John Howard To Eugene McNamara, Mansfield, Texas, 5 February 1962, (1 t.l.s. (carbon) (Box 3, Folder 127)
    - Griffin, John Howard Grand Chief Vutha, (5 page t.ms., with autograph corrections) (Box 4, Folder 138)
    - Grand Chief Vutha To John Howard Griffin, Tutumu[?], 7 July 1944, (2 page a.l.s.) (Box 4, Folder 139)
    - Griffin, John Howard Floridan dialect, [n.p.], [n.d.], (6 pages t.ms. (with photocopy) (Box 4, Folder 140)
      [A list of words and phrases "used by the natives of a group of islands in the South Pacific".
    - Griffin, John Howard Journal entries re. Nuni, (3 pages (photocopy) (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - Daniels, Brad Notes re. Nini, (3 page (photocopy) (Box 3, Folder 129)
    - Nuni, Boston: Houghton Mifflin Co., 1956, (1 vol. Galley proofs (uncorrected) (Box 3, Folder 130)
  - Subseries IV.2: The Street of the Seven Angels
    Concerning Griffin's novels, The Street of the Seven Angels and Passacaglia, it is necessary to outline the genesis of his creative process as regards these works begun in the mid-1950s.. Initially, all of this material was intended for one large novel, tentatively entitled "Point, Counterpoint," but when Griffin heard that Huxley had published a novel with that title, he began to rethink his concept. His journals indicate that the large novel was really made up of alternating chapters with two sets of characters (although a few characters cross from one story to the other). One, which became Street, focused on the character of Chez Durand, a bookshop owner, who becomes involved in an obscenity trial; this story features a large cast of characters and is comic in intent. The second novel, Passacaglia, is a serious work about a concert pianist and his illegitimate son--also a pianist.. The manuscript herein called Passacaolia is actually the remnants of the larger novel (207 pages of typescript carbon) which was never completed. The manuscript of Street of the Seven Angels is a 221 page typescript, an original he revised from portions of the carbon, from 1966-1972. He intended to publish Street as his third novel and even though he came under contract with Houghton Mifflin for the work, it was never published. He never returned to do a revision of Passacaglia. A reading of Street will reveal that it has been revised and completed, but a reading of the carbon of Passacaolia--which has gaps in pagination, as well as many adjustments (as many as five changes on some pages)--never received any revision.
    - Street of the Seven Angels, Texas, 1966-1972, (221 page t.ms.) (Box 3, Folder 131 & 132)
  - Subseries IV.3: Passacaglia
    - Passacaglia, (207 page t.ms. (carbon) (Box 3, Folder 133 & 134)
      [Incomplete. Pages from an unfinished novel
    - Griffin, John Howard Precis of Street of the Seven Angels, 1960s, (8 page t.ms. (carbon) (Box 4, Folder 135)
      [There is also a hand-drawn map by Griffin of the quarter of Paris in which the action takes place. [missing 11/20/2000-PL]
    - Griffin, John Howard Precis of Passacaqlia, 1950s, (8 page t.ms.) (Box 4, Folder 136)
      [Features two page plot outline, and three page character sketches of both the main characters.
    - Griffin, John Howard "Chez Durand", New World Writing, 1957, (10 page photocopy) (Box 4, Folder 137)
- Series V: Land of the High Sky
  This is Griffin's working carbon of the first draft, containing his hand-written changes and cuts. The 336 page manuscript, initially entitled A Land Full of Sky is more than 100 pages longer than the published book. The story of how this book project came into being can be found in the notes by Bradford Daniel.
  - Daniel, Bradford Notes on Land of the High Sky, (2 page photocopy) (Box 4, Folder 141)
  - Griffin, John Howard Land of the High Sky, (366 page t.ms.) (Box 4, Folder 142-152)
    [The following are brief textual notes on the manuscript: The "Preface" was reprinted in The John Howard Griffin Reader. It also discusses the genesis of this unique project.. "Eighteen Covered Wagons" (Chapter I of the manuscript) was cut by one-third for the published book. This book version was reprinted in The Reader and in the anthology, A Part of Space (TCU Press).. "The Frontier Fights West" (Chapter 2 of the manuscript) was divided into four chapters in the book: "Comanche Country" (2), "Frontiersmen Move West" (3), "Struggle to Survive" (4), and "Cattle Country" (5).. "Windmill Town" (Chapter 3 of the manuscript) became Chapter 6 of the book--without any major changes, except that the final 22 mss. pages became Chapter 7 ("Cowboy") in the published version. This chapter about cowboys was reprinted in The Reader.. "The Love Letters of Bessie Love" (pages 228-249 of the manuscript) was cut from the published book. That chapter was published for the first time in The John Howard Griffin Reader.. "Shepherds and Bankers" (Chapter 4 of the manuscript) became Chapter 8. "No Need to Steal" (Chapter 5 of ms.) became Chapter 9 of the book. Both these chapters were published without major cuts and maintained their original titles.. "The Impossible" (Chapter 6 of the manuscript) became Chapter 10 of the book. "Three Booms and A City" (Chapter 7 of the manuscript) became Chapters 11 and 12 of the book; Chapter 12 was entitled "Today and Tomorrow."
  - Griffin, John Howard Journal entry re. Land, (7 page photocopy) (Box 4, Folder 153)
  - Cochran, W. C. Memoir, [Palo Pinto County, TX], [n.d.], (74 page t.ms.) (Box 4, Folder 153A)
    [With Griffin's ms. annotations
  - First National Bank of Midland To Bradford Daniel, Midland, Texas, 16 November 1965, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 4, Folder 154)
    [With related material
  - Bloom Advertising To John Howard Griffin, Dallas, Texas, 1 September 1965, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 4, Folder 155)
  - Butler, John To Beverly Frank, [n.p.], 23 June 1987 (Box 4, Folder 156)
  - Press release, [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 page t.ms.) (Box 4, Folder 157)
  - Rosenfield, John Notes on Land, [n.p.], [n.d.], (2 page t.ms.) (Box 4, Folder 158)
  - Texas Christian University Press Ten Texas writers, Fort Worth, Texas, [n.d.], (1 brochure) (Box 4, Folder 159)
  - Letters and related material sent to John Howard Griffin re. Land of the High Sky, Texas, 1960-1970, (1 a.l.s., 2 t.l.s., 1 t.l., 1 article) (Box 4, Folder 160)
- Series VI: The Decade of the Fifties
  - Griffin, John Howard What happened in Mansfield: a report of the crisis situation in Mansfield, Texas, resulting from efforts to desegregate its school system, Mansfield, TX, [1956], (17 pages t.ms. (mimeograph) (Box 4, Folder 161)
    [This document gives us the background in Mansfield and the historical chronology of the situation from 1948 through 1956; this portion runs for six and one-half pages, followed by one and one-half pages of personal impressions by Griffin. The remainder of the document is made up of interviews with some of the participants, as well as further analysis.
  - Copies of the Baptism and Confirmation certificates of Griffin's conversion to Catholicism., TX, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 162)
  - Copy of marriage certificate of John Howard Griffin, with press clipping re. marriage, Texas, 1953, (2 pages photocopy) (Box 4, Folder 163)
  - News stories re. Griffin regaining his sight, Texas, 1957, (7 pages photocopies) (Box 4, Folder 164)
  - Milhaud, Darius To John Howard Griffin, [n.p.], [1953] (Box 4, Folder 165)
    [The French composer, who was a close friend of the Casadesus family, responds to a letter from Griffin (no carbon of that Griffin letter was in the archives).
  - Poulenc, Francis To John Howard Griffin, 1954-55, (3 pages t.ms. (translations), 4 t.l. (carbons) (Box 4, Folder 166)
    [There are no original Poulenc letters. Poulenc, thinking Griffin was a priest, bared his soul to the young American during the time he was composing his great religious work, "Dialogue of the Carmelites." Included in this folder is a photocopy of Griffin's article, "The Poulenc Behind the Mask," published in Ramparts, in 1964. This piece sets the letters in context and provides perspective to the relationship.
  - Griffin, John Howard To Gerald Vann, Mansfield, Texas, 6 April 1957 - 5 May 1963, (7 t.l. (carbons) (Box 4, Folder 167)
    [Dominican theologian. Father Vann was an early champion of Griffin's first novel, The Devil Rides Outside, defending the book against the criticism of Catholic clergy in the United States and England (Vann was British). Griffin considered Vann to be among his spiritual mentors (along with Jacques Maritain and Thomas Merton), and he was greatly influenced by Fr. Vann's commentary on The Book of John (The Eagle's Word)
  - Murphy, Father Stanley To John Howard Griffin, Windsor, Ontario, 1957-1967, (76 t.l.s. & a.l.s., In 4 folders) (Box 4, Folder 168-171)
    [Father Murphy was director of the Christian Culture Series for nearly 30 years and on the faculty of Assumption University, Windsor, Ontario. Griffin spoke in the series a half dozen times and was awarded the Christian Culture Medal (1966). These letters are vibrant, personal and intelligently opinionated. Fr. Murphy was a loyal defender of Griffin's work and was a radical critic of racism in the Catholic Church. The men were close friends, visited each other every year, and were together with Jacques Maritain and Thomas Merton when those two friends visited for the last time at the Abbey of Gethsemani, in 1966
  - Murphy, Father Stanley "The Born, the Unborn, and the Still-Born," along with an offprint of the essay published by The Basilian Teacher (a magazine of the Basilian order)., Windsor, Ontario, [1962], (7 page t.ms. (carbon), 1 pamphlet) (Box 4, Folder 171)
    [Includes promotional materials from the Christian Culture Series
  - Griffin, John Howard To Father Stanley J. Murphy, Mansfield, Texas, 1957-1963, (71 t.l. (carbons), In 3 folders) (Box 4, Folder 172-174)
    [Included is a significant 8 page letter from 1957; there are 40 letters from 1962, many concerning racism and Black Like Me
  - Turner, Decherd To John Howard Griffin, Dallas, Texas, 1961-1966, (5 t.l.s., 2 page bibliography (carbon) (Box 4, Folder 175)
    [The bibliography is of Griffin's writings
  - Griffin, John Howard To Decherd Turner, Mansfield, TX, 1954-1962, (15 t.l. (carbons) (Box 4, Folder 176)
  - Griffin, John Howard To Nelson Gonzales, [Mansfield, Texas], 12 September 1957, (1 page t.l. (carbon) (Box 4, Folder 177)
    [Inquiring about the possibility of writing a novel of the southwest that "will observe a picture of the daily lives and customs of the Spanish-Americans." However, nothing came of this project.
  - Crossman, Jerome K., et al. Circular letter relating to the controversy between the Dallas Museum of Fine Arts and a group known as the Dallas County Patriotic Council., Texas, 1956, (1 page mimeographed letter, signed) (Box 4, Folder 178)
- Series VII: General Correspondence, 1949-1980
  - Griffin, John Howard To the Gillespie sisters--Sallie, Hannah, and Mary--of Taos, New Mexico. Mansfield, TX, 1949-1964, (276 letters in, 14 folders) (Box 5, Folder 179-192)
    [Often, his salutations simply read "Dear Girls". Griffin includes messages for many of their mutual friends in Taos during those years--the painter Andrew Dasberg and his wife, Helen; the painter Robert Ellis and his wife, Rosa, and daughter, Erendira; as well as other neighbors and friends, many of them also artists and writers. These letters are full of personal disclosures (about his publishers, famous artists, civil rights activists, mutual friends, and family); there is a lot of behind-the-scenes information about Griffin's Published books and working manuscripts, as well as remarks about photography and music. Only about 25 letters from the various Gillespie sisters survive, and these are included in the Series. All three Gillespie sisters have passed away.
  - Sussman, Cornelia and Irving To John Howard Griffin, CA, 1963 - 1980, (240 letters in, 5 folders) (Box 5, Folder 193 - 197)
    [The Sussmans are both writers. Cornelia has four novels to her credit and Irving has two books of literary criticism. As a team, they published their most important books: How To Read A Dirty Book, which discusses both the censorship trials of The Devil Rides Outside and Black Like Me; Profiles in Hope, which has a chapter on Griffin; and their biography of Thomas Merton, published by MacMillan, featuring a Griffin photographic portrait of the monk as its cover.. Griffin considered the Sussmans part of his adopted literary family because they were contemporaries who were conversant with his own spiritual influences: Jacques and Raissa Maritain, Thomas Merton, Robert and Gaby Casadesus, as well as the great saints (in particular, St Thomas Aquinas). He wrote them as freely and openly as he wrote anyone and, during the 1970s, they were his most intimate friends
  - Griffin, John Howard To Cornelia and Irving Sussman, et al., [v.p.], 14 October 1962 - 14 February 1980, (3 volumes) (Box 6, Folder 198-200)
    [These bound volumes were given to Elizabeth Griffin-Bonazzi as a gift from the Sussmans.. There is a photograph of Griffin by Irving Sussman in volume 1 and original photographs throughout
- Series VIII: Black Like Me
  - Griffin, John Howard Original manuscripts of Black Like Me, [n.p.], 1961, (211 page t.ms.) (Box Manuscript Box [Vault])
    [This is the only typescript made by Griffin--from both his Sepia series, "Journey into Shame," and his journals of the aftermath--of the bestseller for which he is best known. The manuscript is in superb condition, separated by fly-sheets, and stored in a manuscript box.. This working copy of the original typescript includes all of the editor's suggestions, as well as the author's revisions
  - Addison Wesley Publishing Co., Inc. To John Howard Griffin, CA, 8 September 1967, (1 t.l.s.) (Box 6, Folder 201)
  - Bunch, Ralph To Anne Ford, New York, 22 August 1961, (1 t.l.s. (copy) (Box 6, Folder 202)
  - Cash, Noel Thomas Account of the hanging of John Howard Griffin's effigy, [n.p.], [n.d.], (9 page a.ms. (photocopy) (Box 6, Folder 203)
    [Cash, a Mansfield resident, who, with several boyhood friends, claim that they are the ones who hung Griffin's effigy in downtown Mansfield after the publication of Black Like Me. The tale is entertaining but not quite convincing. The original manuscript is in the files of the Mansfield Historical Society
  - The Catholic Book Store To John Howard Griffin, New Orleans, 11 August 1961, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6, Folder 204)
  - Citizens for Moral Responsibility Excerpts from Black Like Me, Milwaukee, WI, [n.d.], (2 page t.ms. (photocopy) (Box 6, Folder 205)
  - Clippings re. Black Like Me, [n.p.], 1964-1993, (15 pieces ) (Box 6, Folder Folder 206)
  - Rosica Colin Agency To John Howard Griffin, London, 2 May 1961 - 30 May 1968, (44 t.l.s.) (Box 6, Folder 207-210)
  - William Collins Sons To John Howard Griffin, London, 28 November 1961 - 16 August 1965, (4 t.l.s.) (Box 6, Folder 211)
  - Conover, Ronald Brice To Elizabeth Griffin-Bonazzi, Los Angeles, CA, 15 January 1991, (1 t.l.s. (with photocopy) (Box 6, Folder 212)
  - Cosgrove Meurer Productions, Inc. To Elizabeth Griffin-Bonazzi, CA, 13 July 1990, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 6, Folder 213)
  - The Darnforth Foundation To John Howard Griffin, St. Louis, MO, 22 June 1981, (2 page t.l.s.) (Box 6, Folder 214)
  - ERIC. Columbia University To John Howard Griffin, New York, 28 October 1970, (1 page t.d.s.) (Box 6, Folder 215)
  - Letters re. foreign editions of Black Like Me, [v.p.], 5 December 1961 - 6 June 1968, (3 t.l.s.) (Box 6, Folder 216)
  - Freemantle, Anne Statement on Black Like Me in Commonweal, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 page t.ms. (copy) (Box 6, Folder 217)
  - Geismar, Max Cliff Notes on Black Like Me, [n.p.], [n.d.], (8 page t.ms. (carbon) (Box 6, Folder 218)
  - Griffin, John Howard To Perry Israel, Fort Worth, TX, 4 March 1976, (1 page t.l. (copy) (Box 6, Folder 219)
    [With 2 page enclosure
  - Griffin, John Howard To Superintendent Hungerford, [Texas], 30 May 1969, (1 page t.l.s. (copy) (Box 6, Folder 220)
  - Griffin, John Howard To the Editors, WAY, Mansfield, Texas, 18 July 1966, (2 page t.l. (copy) (Box 6, Folder 221)
  - The Hilltop Company To John Howard Griffin, Washington, D.C., 1 Feb. 1965, (2 page a.l.s.) (Box 6, Folder 222)
    [With enclosures
  - Houghton Mifflin Company To John Howard Griffin, Boston, 16 Feb. 1961 - 23 March 1977, (15 t.l.s.) (Box 6, Folder 223)
  - Houghton Mifflin Company To John Howard Griffin, Boston, 30 Nov. 1961, (1 t.l.s.) (Box 6, Folder 224)
    [Re. damage to negatives
  - Houghton Mifflin Company To John Howard Griffin, Boston, 9 Oct. 1963 - 4 May 1966, (4 t.l.s., 1 telegram) (Box 6, Folder 225)
    [Re. reviews
  - Interracial Review To John Howard Griffin, New York, 27 Nov. & 3 Dec. 1961, (2 t.l.s.) (Box 7, Folder 226)
  - Jesuit Media Associates To Robert and Elizabeth Bonazzi, Los Angeles, CA, 26 July & 30 Nov. 1984, (2 t.l.s.) (Box 7, Folder 227)
  - Johns, Pappas & Flaherty To John Howard Griffin, La Crosse, WI, 12 April 1966 - 3 May 1968, (2 t.l.s., 6 documents) (Box 7, Folder 228)
    [Re. the civil action brought against Griffin accusing him of injuring a 13-year-old boy by writing Black Like Me
  - JM To Mrs. Wilber, [n.p.], 12 Sept. 1967, (1 t.l.) (Box 7, Folder 229)
    [Re. Braille transcription of Black Like Me
  - Landis, Judson R. To John Howard Griffin, Sacramento, CA, 18 Nov. 1970, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 7, Folder 230)
  - Lee, Erik To [Elizabeth Griffin-Bonazzi], Pasadena, CA, 11 Feb. 1992, (2 t.l.s.) (Box 7, Folder 231)
  - Litton Magazines, Inc. To John Howard Griffin, [n.p.], 16 July 1980, (1 page Check request (duplicate) (Box 7, Folder 232)
  - McNamara, Eugene To John Howard Griffin, [n.p.], 7 Sept. 1961, (2 page t.l.s.) (Box 7, Folder 233)
  - Man's Magazine To George Levitan, New York, 6 December 1961, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 7, Folder 234)
  - NAACP To Houghton Mifflin Co., PA, 19 January 1962, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 7, Folder 235)
  - The New American Library To John Howard Griffin, New York, 14 Sept. & 6 Feb. 1968, (2 t.l.s.) (Box 7, Folder 236)
  - Signet To John Howard Griffin, New York, 28 March 1962, (1 telegram) (Box 7, Folder 237)
    [With related items
  - The Redpath Bureau To John Howard Griffin, [v.p.], 25 March 1966 - 17 July 1970, (5 t.l.s.) (Box 7, Folder 238)
  - Rosenfield, Borod, Fones & Bogatin To John Howard Griffin, Memphis, TN, 11 Feb. 1970, (2 page t.l.s.) (Box 7, Folder 239)
  - Rutledge, Don Biographical note, [n.p.], [n.d.], (1 page photocopy) (Box 7, Folder 240)
    [Photographer for Black Like Me
  - Saad, Ted To Elizabeth Griffin-Bonazzi, New York, 26 Aug. 1991, (3 page t.l.s. (copy) (Box 7, Folder 241)
  - Griffin-Bonazzi, Elizabeth To Ted Saad, Mansfield, TX, 29 August 1991, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 7, Folder 241)
  - The Saturday Evening Post To John Howard Griffin, Philadelphia, 8 Dec. 1961 - 8 June 1962, (3 t.l.s.) (Box 7, Folder 242)
  - Saturday Review To John Howard Griffin, New York, 6 March 1962 - 24 July 1963, (3 t.l.s.) (Box 7, Folder 243)